<!--
<i2p.news date="$Date: 2013-10-02 00:00:00 $">
<i2p.release version="0.9.8.1" date="2013/10/02" minVersion="0.6" su2Torrent="magnet:?xt=urn:btih:a5beacbfb0eee65b895de956d39ace48ed17e68f&dn=i2pupdate-0.9.8.1.su2&tr=http://tracker2.postman.i2p/announce.php" />
-->
<div lang="en">
<h3>2013-10-02: <b>0.9.8.1 <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/release-0.9.8.1.html">Released</a></b></h3>

<p>0.9.8.1 fixes a problem with updating to 0.9.8 on Windows for some people.
New installs and non-Windows platforms are not affected, however all platforms
will automatically update even if running 0.9.8.
See the <a href="http://trac.i2p2.i2p/ticket/1056">trac ticket</a> for details and workarounds.
Sorry for the problems!
</p>

<h3>2013-09-30: <b>0.9.8 <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/release-0.9.8.html">Released</a></b></h3>
 
<p>0.9.8 includes the long-awaited support for IPv6. It's enabled by default, 
but of course you need a public IPv6 address to use it. Configuration is on the 
"network" configuration tab in your console.
We also have anonymity improvements including padding of SSU packets and 
longer router private keys.</p>

<p>If you have a public IPv6 address 
and you are connecting to another router with a published IPv6 address, it will 
connect via IPv6. There is a new IPv6 configuration section on <a href="/confignet">/confignet</a>.
If IPv6 is causing problems you may disable it there.</p>

<p>For those of you running I2P on faster hardware (generally, 64-bit x86) the 
router will generate a new identity using longer keys. This will substantially 
reduce your participating traffic for 48 hours or more, while your router 
re-integrates into the network. Due to the new keys, the large number of 
torrent updates, and the recent network growth, we expect substantial 
disruption to the network for a week or more after the update is released. 
Please be patient and things should start to improve after a few days.</p>

<p>We are experiencing rapid network growth in the last few weeks, which is 
causing a bit of a bumpy ride for some, especially on weekends. The 
network is still performing fairly well, so keep spreading the word.
See the <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/release-0.9.8.html">release notes</a>
for more information on IPv6 and rekeying.
Due to recent attacks, logins are disabled on <a href="http://trac.i2p2.i2p/tickets/1">trac</a> and new registrations are disabled on
<a href="http://zzz.i2p/">zzz.i2p</a>. Until those services are restored, please report all bugs on IRC freenode or IRC2P #i2p-dev.
</p>

</div>
