<!--
<i2p.news date="$Date: 2013-05-28 00:00:00 $">
<i2p.release version="0.9.6" date="2013/05/28" minVersion="0.6" su2Torrent="magnet:?xt=urn:btih:04db7bbdb2d294ae356a3ae7dadf7b8fda73de3a&dn=i2pupdate-0.9.6.su2&tr=http://tracker2.postman.i2p/announce.php" sudTorrent="magnet:?xt=urn:btih:9318bcfcf1f2242f219d9e1c0bdb73c415190de4&dn=i2pupdate-0.9.6.sud&tr=http://tracker2.postman.i2p/announce.php" />
-->
<div lang="en">
<h3>2013-05-28: <b>0.9.6 <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/release-0.9.6.html">Released</a></b></h3>

<p>0.9.6 includes bug fixes and an update from Jetty 6.1.26 (2010-11-10) to Jetty 7.6.10 (2013-03-12).
 See below for important information on the Jetty update. The Jetty 7 series is actively maintained and
 we plan to stay current with it in future I2P releases.</p>

<p>Most users will update via HTTP. Those running development builds will attempt to update via the
 experimental in-network bittorrent with i2psnark. We've fixed some bugs that will enable more users
 to update via torrent in the 0.9.7 update cycle.</p>

<p><strong>Important fix for Windows Eepsites, first install 0.9.5 only</strong></p>

<p>If you first installed I2P with version 0.9.5, on Windows only, we recommend that you follow the
 following instructions to fix your eepsite location <strong>before</strong> you update to 0.9.6.
 Only original installations of 0.9.5-0 on Windows are affected by this issue. If your router version
 is 0.9.5-0-win1, you already have the fix and need not take any action.
<br />See <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/ticket919">www.i2p2.i2p/ticket919</a>
 or <a href="http://www.i2p2.de/ticket919">www.i2p2.de/ticket919</a> for instructions.</p>

<p><strong>Jetty 7 Migration Details</strong></p>

<p><strong> For most people, the update should just work. If you have multiple Jetty eepsites,
 OR have made changes to jetty.xml or other Jetty configuration files, including changing the port
 from 7658, you MUST take manual action AFTER updating.</strong></p>

<p>* After update, the router will migrate your jetty.xml files to the new Jetty 7 format.</p>

<p>* The migration resets the port to 7658. If you have more than one Jetty eepsite, OR your eepsite
 is NOT on port 7658, OR you have made other modifications to jetty.xml (for example changing the
 listen address from 127.0.0.1 to 0.0.0.0), you MUST edit the jetty.xml file for each eepsite to fix them up
 after updating, and restart again.</p>

<p><strong>The following files will be backed up with a &quot;.jetty6&quot; suffix and then migrated.</strong>
 If you have made local changes, you may have to edit them manually and restart.
 See <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/Jetty">http://wiki.eclipse.org/Jetty</a> for assistance
 in configuring Jetty 7.</p>

<p>* ~/.i2p/clients.config
<br />* ~/.i2p/eepsite/jetty.xml
<br />* ~/.i2p/eepsite/jetty-rewrite.xml
<br />* ~/.i2p/eepsite/jetty-ssl.xml
<br />* ~/.i2p/eepsite/contexts/base-context.xml
<br />* ~/.i2p/eepsite/contexts/cgi-context.xml
<br />* ~/.i2p/eepsite/etc/webdefault.xml</p>

<p><strong>Plugins</strong></p>

<p>Most plugins should work fine with Jetty 7.
 The I2PControl and zzzot plugins must be updated. Your router should download and install
 the new versions shortly after starting 0.9.6.
 If a plugin does not work, please contact the maintainer for that plugin.

</p><p>
Say hello to the volunteers on the <a href="irc://127.0.0.1:6668/i2p-help">#i2p-help IRC channel</a>.
<a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/getinvolved.html">Get involved</a>,
spread the word,
and <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/donate.html">donate</a>!
If you find a bug, please enter a report on <a href="http://trac.i2p2.i2p/report/1">trac</a>.
To help on translations,
volunteer on <a href="irc://127.0.0.1:6668/i2p">IRC #i2p-dev</a>
or sign up on <a href="https://www.transifex.net/projects/p/I2P/">Transifex</a>.
</p>
</div>
