<!--
<i2p.news date="$Date: 2015-11-19 18:00:00 $">
<i2p.release version="0.9.23" date="2015/11/19" minVersion="0.9.9" minJavaVersion="1.6" su3Torrent="magnet:?xt=urn:btih:efb353858e125a73c14ec3a079f78aebc2ff4176&dn=i2pupdate-0.9.23.su3&tr=http://tracker2.postman.i2p/announce.php" />
-->
<div lang="en">
<h3>2015-11-19: <b>0.9.23 <a href="http://i2p-projekt.i2p/en/blog/post/2015/11/19/0.9.23-Release">Released</a></b></h3>
<p>
Hello I2P! This is the first release signed by me (str4d), after 49 releases
signed by zzz. This is an important test of our redundancy for all things,
including people.
</p>
<p><b>Housekeeping</b></p>
<p>
My signing key has been in router updates for over two years (since 0.9.9), so
if you are on a recent version of I2P this update should be just as easy as
every other update. However, if you are running an older version than 0.9.9, you
will first need to manually update to a recent version. Update files for recent
versions can be downloaded
<a href="http://whnxvjwjhzsske5yevyokhskllvtisv5ueokw6yvh6t7zqrpra2q.b32.i2p/releases/">here</a>,
and instructions on how to manually update are provided
<a href="http://i2p-projekt.i2p/en/download#update">here</a>. Once you have manually
updated, your router will then find and download the 0.9.23 update as usual.
</p><p>
If you installed I2P via a package manager, you are not affected by the change,
and can update as usual.
</p>
<p><b>Update details</b></p>
<p>
The migration of RouterInfos to new, stronger Ed25519 signatures is going well,
with at least half of the network already estimated to have rekeyed. This
release accelerates the rekeying process. To reduce network churn, your router
will have a small probability of converting to Ed25519 at each restart. When it
does rekey, expect to see lower bandwidth usage for a couple of days as it
reintegrates into the network with its new identity.
</p><p>
Note that this will be the last release to support Java 6. Please update to
Java 7 or 8 as soon as possible. We are already working to make I2P compatible
with the upcoming Java 9, and some of that work is in this release.
</p><p>
We have also made some minor improvements in I2PSnark, and added a new page in
the routerconsole for viewing older news items.
</p><p>
As usual, we recommend that you update to this release. The best way to
maintain security and help the network is to run the latest release.
</p>
</div>
