<!--
<i2p.news date="$Date: 2013-07-15 00:00:00 $">
<i2p.release version="0.9.7" date="2013/07/15" minVersion="0.6" su2Torrent="magnet:?xt=urn:btih:33153132e9c231e65d51235478127ab289349002&dn=i2pupdate-0.9.7.su2&tr=http://tracker2.postman.i2p/announce.php" sudTorrent="magnet:?xt=urn:btih:97b2cdd241e58b2e098c20997f2e78405a71cbfa&dn=i2pupdate-0.9.7.sud&tr=http://tracker2.postman.i2p/announce.php" />
-->
<div lang="en">
<h3>2013-07-15: <b>0.9.7 <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/release-0.9.7.html">Released</a></b></h3>

<p>0.9.7 includes significant bug fixes and improvements.

For the first time, class 'N' routers (those with a minimumum of 128 KBytes/sec of shared bandwidth)
 will automatically become floodfill (previously it was only 'O' routers with 256 KBps). This will
 increase the floodfill population for additional resistance to certain attacks (see below). Floodfill routers
 don't consume much additional bandwidth, but they do tend to use additional memory and concurrent
 connections. If you do not wish your router to become floodfill, set the advanced configuration
 router.floodfillParticipant=false .</p>

<p>The last release fixed the experimental update-via-torrent bugs, 3% of routers should
 update over in-network bittorrent this cycle.
Plugin update checks, possibly broken for several releases, are fixed. Your plugins should once again
 auto-update after updating the router.
We fixed a major streaming timer bug that contributed to frequent IRC disconnects.</p>

<p>
This release contains additional mitigations for the
<a href="http://wwwcip.informatik.uni-erlangen.de/~spjsschl/i2p.pdf">"practical attacks" paper</a>.
However, we have a lot more work to do to resist Sybil attacks
and traffic analysis by the floodfills.
It's a good reminder that our network is still relatively small and vulnerable.
We don't currently recommend any uses that would put anybody in serious jeopardy.
We'll keep working to improve it... please keep working to spread the word. A bigger network is a better network.

</p><p>
Say hello to the volunteers on the <a href="irc://127.0.0.1:6668/i2p-help">#i2p-help IRC channel</a>.
<a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/getinvolved.html">Get involved</a>,
and <a href="http://www.i2p2.i2p/donate.html">donate</a>!
If you find a bug, please enter a report on <a href="http://trac.i2p2.i2p/report/1">trac</a>.
To help on translations,
volunteer on <a href="irc://127.0.0.1:6668/i2p">IRC #i2p-dev</a>
or sign up on <a href="https://www.transifex.net/projects/p/I2P/">Transifex</a>.
</p>
</div>
